[ Sleigh bells jingle ]
NARRATOR : That night ,
penetrating deep into the heart of Transylvania ,
Professor Abronsius was unaware
that he was on the point of reaching the goal
of his mysterious investigations ,
in the course of which
he had journeyed throughout central Europe for many years
accompanied by his one and only faithful disciple ,
Alfred ...
A scholar and scientist
whose genius was unappreciated .
Abronsius had given up all to devote himself body and soul
to what was to him a sacred mission .
He had even lost his chair at Königsberg University
where for a long time
his colleagues used to refer to him
as the nut .
[ Wolf howls ]
[ Louder howling ]
[ Squeaks ]
[ Dog snarls ]
[ Teeth snapping , growling ]
[ Laughter and voices ]
Welcome !
[ Laughing ]
Professor .
Quick , quick !
Oh !
MAN : Hurry , hurry !
MAN 2 : Here !
MAN 3 : No , no , over here .
MAN : Don 't push me !
Not against his skull because of gangrene !
Hot beer ! Hot beer and cinnamon !
Gently ! It will break like glass !
A mustard bath for his feet !
His nose as well . His nose as well .
No ! Not the nose !
MAN 4 : Stand him up ! Stand him up !
MAN 5 : No !
Rebecca !
Where is the Bikos for the gentleman , no ?
It 's ready , it 's ready !
We drive on a little further
until we get to bubuski ...
now we get to fulidnish ...
[ Man continues tale indistinctly ]
Garlic .
Garlic , my boy . Garlic .
ALFRED : You think ...
[ Professor cheerfully ] Without a doubt .
Here .
Eh-i-is it finished ?
Yes , it 's finished .
D-d-w-wait , wait , wait .
We don 't go to Brevarsky ?
- Hmm ? - To Brevarsky .
- No , no , no . - We don 't go to Iski ?
No , no , no , not to Iski , no .
... The whole winter if need be .
Indeed , the summer as well .
It 's a home away from home , no ?
- Tell me , uh ... - I 'm telling you !
- Listen , you 've got ... - The garlic .
- Eh , garlic . - No , no , no .
What is all the garlic doing here ?
Where ?
Ah ... yes ...
YOYNEH : Not garlic , professor .
Please , not garlic .
Is there by any chance a castle
in the district ?
[ Chuckling ] By any chance a castle
On the word of Yoyneh ,
there 's no more a castle here
than a windmill .
[ Laughing ]
Does anybody here know
a windmill in the district , huh ?
No ?
You see ? And a castle ,
anybody know a castle ?
There 's a castle ...
YOYNEH : You see ?
No castle , no windmill .
Eat , eat , eat , huh ?
The Bikos is good , huh , you like ?
Eat ! Look , the little one , he 's eating .
You see ?
You got the best room in the house
with its own bathroom . Come .
You 'll be very warm , nice ...
Comfortable .
Please , just take a look .
I 've forgotten Sarah !
I mean , this bath will be free when this ...
I promise , it will be free tomorrow .
Tomorrow , professor .
Use the conveniences in the corridor ,
last door on the left .
Goodbye , gentlemen .
PROFESSOR : Dear boy !
All these signs !
We are nearing our goal at last !
We are nearing our goal !
Uh-oh .
Last door on the left , huh ?
[ Whispers ] We are nearing our goal .
SARAH : No !
[ Yoyneh yells ]
YOYNEH : ... To stay in your room !
But you always take a bath !
SARAH : No !
[ Screams ] No ! No !
[ Yoyneh yelling ]
SARAH : I won 't ! I won 't , papa !
[ Yelling and slapping sounds ]
I told you every day you are having baths !
I told you no bath !
No bath ! No bath ! No bath !
[ Woman sobs ]
Now you 've got it .
[ Soft snoring ]
Incredible .
Read this .
[ Clears throat ]
" According to E ... Elibori ,
" they cast no reflected image .
" Thus for example , one cannot see them
" nor can they see themselves
in the mirror . "
[ Chuckles ]
In the mirror ... In the mirror ...
Mirror .
" Nor in any other object serving
the same purpose like water ,
- window panes , etcetera . " - [ Creaking ]
Water , window panes ...
What 's next ? What 's next ?
- Shh . - [ Creaking ]
[ Whispers ] Someone is walking the corridor .
[ Creaking ]
Quickly , get them off ! Get them off !
[ Woman hums ]
♪ ♪ La la la la hum la la la ♪ ♪
Ah , tch , tch , tch , tch .
Always singing .
What 's my good little fairy up to ?
What 's she doing , eh ?
Your good little fairy
is mending your night shirt .
This night shirt is mine ?
No ... yes ?
That 's good . It 's perfect as it is .
I 'll try it on .
If you try your nightshirt in my room ,
I scream .
[ Zzz ... snort ]
Yoyneh !
[ Rustling ]
Hurry , hurry !
Forget about the buttons .
[ Creaking ]
Shh !
[ Rooster crows ]
[ Snores ]
[ Hammering ]
[ Hammering continues ]
[ Children yell ]
[ Door opens ]
[ Dog barks ]
Hoo hoo !
[ Indistinct muttering ]
That hunchback , Alfred .
That hunchback . Did you notice ?
Eh . Revolting .
Why were you under the table ?
Oh !
I think we have a clue !
I want you to follow him .
I am not completely daft , you know .
I am telling you .
Someone last night bashed me on the skull .
I don 't see a bump .
[ Whinnying ]
[ Hideous scream ]
[ Whip cracks ]
[ Snoring ]
[ Knock on door ]
[ Snoring continues ]
I 'm not disturbing you , am I ?
Not at all , not at all .
SARAH : I ... I just
don 't know what to do with myself .
I get so bored .
You can 't imagine how bored I get .
Don 't know .
I 'm just not used to being locked up the whole time .
You mean you 're always locked up ?
SARAH : At school ...
We had fun there .
We used to skip over the wall .
Did all kinds of things .
ALFRED : Yeah ?
You know what I mean .
Then ... papa ...
Don 't know what happened to papa .
My room ... my room is full of garlic .
He says it looks pretty .
[ Sarcastically ] Pretty .
I brought it back from school .
Oh . It 's a ...
Good one .
Soft .
SARAH : Listen ...
I ... I adore it .
I ... I got into the habit of it at school .
He 's funny , papa .
You just can 't change your habits
in a couple of months , can you ?
Besides ...
It 's good for your hair ...
Once a day at the very least .
Don 't you agree ?
Yes . [ Chuckling ]
Do you mind if ... I have a quick one ?
Huh ?
I don 't mind at all , but ...
Oh , thank you . You 're being very nice .
Now could you get me some hot water ?
[ Can clatters ]
WOMAN : Where are you going ?
I 'm not going !
Thank you .
[ Snoring ]
[ Squealing ]
I saw him ! I saw him !
He 's there !
There !
YOYNEH : Sarah !
[ Squealing ]
[ Sobs ] Your excellency !
Your excellency Von Krolock !
Give me back my daughter !
Give her back to me !
[ Sobbing ]
Your excellency !
Little Sarah ! Excellency !
Shagal , Shagal !
YOYNEH : My little girl !
Shagal .
[ Sobbing ] I beg yo ... Ou ... Ou .
[ Woman screaming ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Sobbing ]
Careful . Take care . Careful .
[ Whimpers ] Careful .
[ Sleigh bells jingling ]
[ Farm animals make commotion ]
[ Knock on door ]
What ?
Yoyneh !
Oy ! Oy ! Oy !
[ Screams and cries ]
[ Woman cries ]
Look , Alfred .
They have drained him
in the twinkling of an eye .
WOODCUTTER : They are mighty fierce this winter ,
the beasts .
We ought to organize a beat .
Found one in the f-forest
w-w-with the throat
ripped !
WOODCUTTER 2 : Now they have taken
to devouring each other .
Poor Shagal , to end
in the jaws of a wolf .
A wolf .
A wolf !
You blind wretches !
Open your eyes !
You know perfectly well who has been at work .
Ripped .
Oh , you 're poor victims
of your own cowardice !
Stick it where ?
Alas , Madame Shagal ,
I have already explained to you .
The body of Mr. Shagal is destroyed ,
but one can save his soul ...
By sticking it in .
- Sticking it in ? - Yes .
- Where ? - In the heart .
According to the works of Elibori
and my own personal researches , by the way ,
it is the only way . Like this in one go .
Whack .
- Not . - Yes !
The works of Elibori .
In whose heart ?
Sticking it in ...
In my Yoyneh 's heart ?
Stick in my Yoyneh 's heart ?
You hear , Yoyneh ? This swine wants me
to stick this shank in your heart !
[ Menacingly ] Oh ...
You stupid old goat !
Stick it ? ! I 'll stick this
right through you , you old fool !
I will !
[ Thunk ]
- [ Thunk ] - Aah !
Are you blind ? !
[ Giggling ]
[ Squealing ]
1 , 2 , 3 !
Blast it !
He 's gone ?
Not bad , this little wine .
[ Wheezy laugh ]
Have you got the wrong vampire !
[ Laughing ]
There ! In there .
Ah . [ Hiccup ] I thought so .
Another mad jackal ... Ah , Shagal .
We must all get down to work .
Of course , we shall need your assistance .
First we must block out the window .
Ah . Good . Good .
Next , garlic .
Plenty of garlic everywhere .
And some crucifixes .
[ Giggles ]
I 'll lend you some .
Tomorrow I will see to the transfusion .
Is everything clear ?
Well , let me repeat .
The garlic . Uh ... Window blocked . Uh ...
Crucifix here ...
There .
There . Hmm ? [ Hiccup ]
- Professor ? - What ?
The other way around . The other way around .
Yo-yo-d-d-d ...
[ Lighthearted music ]
[ Ominous chords ]
[ Alfred whimpers ]
ALFRED : I can feel something soft .
[ Professor whispering ] Where are you ?
ALFRED : Here .
PROFESSOR : Huh ?
[ Shuffling footsteps ]
- ALFRED : Here . -
PROFESSOR : Oh .
It 's a curtain !
[ Shuffling ]
- [ Clunk ] - Ooh !
There is a door behind it .
I have a funny feeling ...
We are being watched .
Ah , chh .
Oh ! Since you are here , my friend ,
perhaps you could tell me ...
[ Locks door ]
[ Moans ] Oh ...
[ Stool falls ]
[ Wolf howls ]
So this is how
one worms one 's way into my castle .
Well , to be precise , sir ...
Count ...
Von Krolock .
[ Loud clatter ]
" Professor Abronsius .
Königsberg University . "
This alters everything .
I have had the opportunity of reading your work ...
A bat ; its mysteries .
No , really ?
VON KROLOCK : Remarkable .
I must have a copy somewhere .
I would like you to inscribe it for me .
I ...
Well ... your ...
Excellency is ... Too kind .
VON KROLOCK : So you lost your way ?
No ! Actually , we were running after ...
VON KROLOCK : You were running after ...
A Pteropus .
Yes ! We were running after a Pteropus .
Fancy that .
I thought bats fell into a deep sleep
throughout the winter months .
Oh , not always . Not always , your excellency .
Nevertheless , that is what I read in your book .
PROFESSOR : Precisely , so you can understand
the amazement of my assistant and myself .
We could not believe our eyes .
Isn 't that so , Alfred ?
Oh , we couldn 't . It ... Was like ...
Now , imagine ...
A Chiroptera flitting about in December ?
Incredible !
What 's more is ...
It was as big as ... This .
Wasn 't it , Alfred ?
Like ...
Of course , the case is not unique .
In my second volume ... Actually at the printer 's ...
I cite several analogous cases
supplied to me by reputable colleagues
such as falkman at Munich up to athener of Prague .
VON KROLOCK : Curious ...
Curious , yes , but in no way inexplicable .
I think we can look for the cause
in the purely mechanical need to
fight against the Torpor of Hibernation ...
To restore circulation
by primary motion ...
To cause the vital limbs to work
without thinking .
This , in consequence ,
makes them ... Fly
without being aware of it .
Of course , I only refer to the very rare species
not conforming to the Laws of Hibernation .
[ Rooster crows ]
Rather like sleepwalkers ?
PROFESSOR : Yes !
That 's to say , they fly in their sleep .
[ Bell dinging ]
I had an aunt who was a sleepwalker .
At night , she frequently ran about on the battlements
without causing me any surprise
because there was actual contact .
But the walking isn 't flying .
How is it possible
to avoid an obstacle when flying
while being simultaneously asleep ?
[ Chuckles ]
Your excellency ...
It is a very great ability .
The natural sciences greatly interested me ...
When I was a young man .
My library .
Oh !
Ah !
VON KROLOCK : It 's at your disposal .
To fly in one 's sleep , you say .
How is it possible ?
The rays .
Rays ?
[ Grunting and wheezing ]
Gentlemen , Koukol informs me
that your beds are prepared .
Oh , your excellency ,
we have kept you up very late .
I 'm a night bird .
I am not much good in the daytime .
Their little heads
contain a fantastic mechanism , sort of ...
Anyway , this mechanism emits the rays ,
the nature of which escapes me for the moment ,
but one thing is absolutely certain ...
That these rays come into contact
with every obstacle in the way
and rebound off that obstacle
back into their little heads
and warn them , eh ?
That would explain
why they can fly in utter darkness .
- Exactly ! - [ Door opens ]
- [ Gasp ] Ah ! - Oh !
Herbert , my son .
Good evening .
Here is your room .
And this one is for you .
[ Whispers ] Wha ...
The rooms ...
Communicate .
[ Rooster crows ]
Good night , gentlemen .
The fellow is no fool , you know .
Did you hear how he held his own ...
On the subject of the bats , eh ? Ah !
Really sound arguments .
[ Groans ]
Not like those morons from Königsberg .
You see , my boy ?
Ah ...
- Professor ? - Eh ?
[ Clears throat ]
Aren 't we going to barricade ?
Nope . I don 't think
that would be very good tactics .
[ Chuckles ] I thought we were going to barricade .
No , the best thing
is to sleep with one eye open
or to take a watch in turns .
Wha ... hmm ?
Wha-iz-it ?
What are you doing ?
I 'm going to bed .
What has come over you ? Go to your own bed !
Alone ?
Go !
We can keep the door open .
At the slightest alarm ...
We 'll call out .
[ Woman sings haunting melody in distance ]
[ Singing gets louder ]
[ Haunting melody continues ]
[ Singing stops ]
[ Whimpers ]
[ Thump ]
[ Thudding and scuttling ]
[ Humming ]
[ Mutters happily ]
Oy ...
Oy yoy yoy .
[ Grunts ]
Huh ?
Mr. Koukol ,
I 'm not disturbing a soul here !
[ Grunts ]
There 's plenty of room .
People can pass .
- [ Grunts ] - [ Grunts ]
What are you doing ?
Where ... where are you taking me ?
M-Mr . Koukol !
Please !
[ Grunting ]
Mr. Koukol ,
what are you doing to me , please ?
I beg of you ...
Look , I ...
Oy !
Please , it 's not comfortable here .
It 's dirty here .
Look , the day 's coming !
There 's too much light here for me .
Mr. Koukol ...
[ Horse whinnying ]
So ... Now you are satisfied , eh ?
What can you do with such people ?
Hunchback swine !
What does it cost him ...
Doesn 't cost him anything .
He could leave me in there .
Why does he bring me here ?
[ Whimpers and mutters ]
[ Rooster crows ]
[ Wind howls ]
ALFRED : Sarah ...
[ Mumbles ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Clattering ]
He 's got a nerve .
A nerve ?
Von Krolock . He 's brazen .
You remember last night , hmm ?
" I am a nightbird .
I am not much good in the daytime . "
That 's what he said .
Yeah ? So what ?
[ Laughing ] It 's obvious !
During the daytime he rests .
He reposes .
Reposes ?
In the crypt with his fellows !
Maybe there is no crypt in this castle .
Don 't be foolish .
A castle without a crypt
is like a unicorn without a horn .
You 're not going to start arguing with me
like my colleagues from Königsberg , eh ?
Oh ... [ crack ]
Ah !
Oh , first-rate , this bed , huh ?
Did you sleep well , huh ?
[ Gasps ]
I heard singing .
Well , that is no reason to look so worried , huh ?
I 'm sure it was Sarah . Sarah , yes .
Ah , hmm . Sure it 's Sarah ?
Sarah , Shagal 's daughter .
Oh , yes , of course ! [ Laughing ]
I must confess I rather enjoy luxury .
All these years running ...
Uphill and ...
Down Dale , debating with morons .
Trying to convince a ... a pack of fools !
Oh , and the expense .
Perpetual expense .
I 'm sure it was Sarah .
Do you know what that robber Shagal
charges us for board and lodging , huh ?
Her father ?
$ 4.00 , my boy .
Yes , by Jupiter .
4 a day .
Bed without breakfast .
The ruffian . Ah !
Ah ! [ Crack ]
Do you feel in good shape at least ?
Yes .
We 've got a lot on our plate .
To find Sarah ?
Now keep calm .
The crypt comes first .
But what about Sarah ?
We mustn 't put the cart before the horse .
[ Sawing ]
[ Sawing stops ]
[ Scraping ]
[ Scraping continues ]
[ Tapping ]
What 's he up to ?
He 's woodworking .
But it 's ... It 's a coffin !
[ Hammering ]
Oh ! Footprints !
ALFRED : She 's dead .
PROFESSOR : Eureka !
Dead ... Dead ...
Who is dead ?
Sarah .
When ?
Hmm ?
What when ?
- Sarah 's dead . - [ Gasps ]
Oh , my god !
Where is she ?
I don 't know .
What are you driveling about ?
How can you tell me she 's dead
when you say you don 't know ?
The coffin , it 's ... For her .
No , no , no , no .
They are still working on it .
If she were dead , she would already
be in it like one of them ,
screened from the light .
She 's not dead ?
Work it out for yourself .
You may be sure
they 'll make her last out
as long as they can .
- But ... - Their idea of fun .
In that case , who is the cof-coffin for ?
Oh , for her or ...
[ Tapping ]
PROFESSOR : You don 't want to look at him .
Behave naturally .
Recite for me the 12 signs of the zodiac .
Eh ... leo , virgo ,
gemini , cancer ...
White boar ...
What are you talking about ?
[ Sucks air through teeth ]
No panic .
This lout guards the crypt
like a Cerberus .
We must , uh , think of a Stratagem .
Just whistle as if nothing has happened ,
and let 's turn back .
[ Whistling ]
Not ... so fast .
[ Gasps ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Strangled gasps ]
I am stuck .
You have to help me , my boy .
Ooh !
[ Gasping ]
[ Choking ]
[ Retching ]
Imbecile !
I can 't get a grip .
You will have to operate on your own .
- Operate on my own ? - Yes !
What is to be done ?
The stakes , my boy .
The stakes ?
These stakes ?
What other stakes could there be ?
They must be driven in .
By me ?
They 're not going to drive themselves in on their own !
Not that , master ! Please , not that !
Now my boy , show some guts !
I 'm here .
First , you must remove the lids .
Oh , mama .
Remove the lids ?
It 's an order .
Go on !
Open it , for heaven 's sake !
I can 't , master .
PROFESSOR : For the sake of Shagal 's daughter ,
open it !
[ Whispers ] Open your eyes !
Open your eyes !
Who is it ?
His excellency .
PROFESSOR : Good . Now , the other one .
And ... This one ?
His excellency 's son .
And ...
PROFESSOR : Eh ?
And what ?
[ Scoffs ]
ALFRED : Shagal !
Ah ? He 's there ?
Very well .
Open the case .
Pick up a stake .
And a hammer .
Now ... Go do the count .
Search for the right spot in between
the seventh and eighth on the left .
Don 't forget .
Place the stake over the spot .
[ Angrily ] Not upside down !
That 's it !
Raise the hammer ...
And ... strike !
S-s-strike !
Oh , mutiny , is it , huh ?
I will take an oath if there is mutiny .
[ Soothingly ] Ah , come on , my baby , hit .
There 's a good little scout , huh ?
Are you going to hit it or not ,
you good for nothing ...
[ Loud clattering ]
All right . Whew .
Everything back in the case .
It 's no use .
You will have to pull me out
from the other side , dumbbell !
Mind he doesn 't catch you .
[ Woman singing ]
[ Singing is louder ]
[ Water splashing ]
[ Splashing ]
Sarah !
It 's you !
Oh ... [ Chuckling ]
Sarah .
I ... I 'm going to save you .
We 'll go away together .
Where do you want us to go ?
I don 't know .
To ... To your parents ' , perhaps .
They say papa
will be coming to see me soon .
They said that ?
Yes . You 've ... You 've seen my dress ?
Beautiful , isn 't it ?
Very beautiful .
They gave it to me for the ball tonight .
Ball ?
The midnight ball .
This evening , here ? A ball ?
At midnight ?
They 'll all be there .
But we can still have a dance together , you know ?
Sarah , you must follow me .
Follow you ?
I beseech you .
Well ... tomorrow , perhaps .
But ... tomorrow will be too late .
Turn around .
Sar ... [ cough ]
Sarah ?
May I turn around ?
My head is ... Is swimming around .
I 'm no longer the age
for this sort of activity .
Look ! How wonderful nature is .
Yes . Wonderful .
The sun is setting .
Glorious ! Magnificent !
Ah , the sun is setting ,
and they are going to rise .
It 's in the order of things .
[ Dogs howl ]
Oh , what a pity not to have the time .
Once I get stuck into it ,
I am engulfed for a week !
Eh , this way , master .
Wait .
[ Chuckling ]
Pretty well equipped , huh ?
Oh !
ALFRED : Professor ...
Oh ... oh ...
Here is Orion !
Ah !
And here is Saturn with its ring !
Ah . Come !
Come and have a look , my boy .
There it is !
[ Woman singing ]
PROFESSOR : Oh !
Oh . Eh , courage , my good woman , courage .
Oh !
Oh ...
Hah .
Bless my soul .
Shiver my timbers !
Oh . Unless they barricade thoroughly ...
I know what I am talking abo ... out .
[ Haunting melody continues ]
[ Singing is louder ]
[ Plumbing squeaks ]
Sarah ?
Are you ill ?
How pale he is !
I 'm not pale .
Yes , you are , yes , you are .
I assure you .
You are as white as a sheet .
- No ! - Yes , Alfred .
You must have a rest .
Have a little rest ,
and you 'll feel much , much better .
I don 't like to see you in this state .
There , now .
Feeling better ?
Eh ... Isn 't there a ball tonight ?
How long they are .
They look like golden threads .
Huh ?
Your lashes .
[ Whispers ] My lash ...
Golden ...
HERBERT : Who told you
there 's going to be a ball tonight ?
Nobody . I 'm just guessing .
With a great castle like this ,
it 's possible , isn 't it ?
He 's just guessing . But it 's true .
You 've guessed correctly
with your pretty little head .
Yes , Alfred ,
there 's going to be a ball ,
and you 'll be able to dance !
♪ ♪ La la la la la la ♪ ♪
What is it you 're clutching there
like a little treasure ?
Here . Show me .
Alfred , show me .
So , that 's the big secret .
Somebody is in love .
Somebody 's little heart
is beating around in their bosom .
Pitter-pat , pitter-pat , pitter-pat ,
like a rat in a cage .
" 70th way .
" Place the left arm
" around the shoulders of the loved one .
" Put the left hand on the left shoulder
like a little birdy alighting on a branch . "
Good . Excellent .
" Then let an angel pass . "
Shall we allow an angel to pass ?
" Once the angel has passed ,
" bend the face towards the locks
" of the loved one ,
and brush them with the lips . "
[ Groaning growl ]
[ Screaming ]
ALFRED : Close the door !
- Playing games ? - Close the door ! Close the door !
[ Footsteps run by ]
He went Berserk .
Did you provoke him , or what ?
No .
He got excited all on his own .
PROFESSOR : On his own . On his own .
ALFRED : Oh , I meant to tell you ...
What ?
Elibori 's theory is correct .
Which one ?
Eh ... The one to do with the reflections .
In the mirror ...
explain yourself more clearly .
ALFRED : I was ...
In front of a mirror ,
sitting on the edge of the bed , and ...
And , well ... I was alone .
Yet he was by my side , but nothing from him .
No reflection . Nothing . Blank .
Not even his clothes ?
Not even his shirt .
I 'd love to have seen that . Tch .
One doesn 't see a thing .
You found something to eat ?
I ? No .
There is a smell of garlic sausage .
Oh , uh ...
hmm .
ALFRED : Good gracious !
I ... I 'm ...
I 'm frightened .
PROFESSOR : It 's quite impressive .
ALFRED : You think they all are ...
PROFESSOR : Undoubtedly !
ALFRED : Oh , my god .
VON KROLOCK : You should never have come here .
So why did we come ?
VON KROLOCK : Ask the professor .
Oh , so you 're here . You 're here .
If you have no objection ,
I 'm not hibernating .
You don 't seem very pleased .
I am surprised .
Keep your surprise for later on .
You 'll need it .
You didn 't foresee this
in your second volume still at the printer 's .
It will be my pleasure to fill in the gaps
in your learning .
When you attain my spiritual level ,
we shall then have the long winter evenings
before us for our discussions ...
The long ... Evenings ...
Of many winters ...
Your young assistant
will make an excellent companion for my son .
He 's already quite fond of him .
He 's told me so .
He 's a gentle ... Sensitive youth .
In the course of the centuries ,
they will learn to know each other better
just as we shall .
[ Sleigh bells jingle ]
As Brooks flow into streams ,
streams into rivers ,
and rivers into the sea ,
so our adepts flow back to us
and swell our ranks .
Soon we shall be victorious
and triumphant !
We shall then hold sway over this earth
which awaits our coming
as Autumn awaits winter .
[ Sneezing ]
Look at him , almost an old man ,
with his flabby stomach
and spindly legs ,
bring with dog-like devotion
a fresh adept ,
who only a few nights ago
was under his protection .
Look well at this man
who secreted another girl more closely
than a miser hoarding his gold .
- Sarah . - [ Laughing ]
But tonight he 's happy .
See how he frisks and capers ?
Ooh !
I must leave you now .
See you later , gentlemen .
Meditate
while awaiting your turn ,
for it would be extremely difficult
for you to get away from here ,
unless , of course , you have wings .
Like a bat .
[ Door locking ]
[ Mutters prayer ]
He displeased me as much this evening
as he impressed me the first time .
[ Harpsichord playing ]
What they deserve is ...
A good cannonball right in the ...
[ Praying ]
Quick , help me turn it around !
A little more .
More . Ah !
Would you mind giving me a hand !
Good .
Put the wood under the Cannon !
[ Harpsichord playing ]
Under the Cannon . Under the Cannon .
Takes me for a Nincompoop .
That necrophile .
[ Continues playing ]
[ Stops playing ]
A year ago ...
A year ago , exactly on the same night ,
we were assembled here in this very room ,
I , your pastor , and you , my beloved flock .
With hopefulness in my heart , I told you then
that with Lucifer 's aid ,
we might look forward to a more succulent occasion .
Cast back your minds .
There we were ,
gathered together , gloomy and despondent ,
around that single meager Woodcutter .
A year has elapsed ,
and also travelers turn up
more and more seldom in these parts .
In spite of this ,
I have this evening a great ...
A wonderful surprise for you !
Dearly beloved brethren ,
come closer .
[ Crowd gasping ]
This isn 't all !
Yet another human is at this very moment ,
being groomed ...
- CROWD : Ahh ! - And ...
And ... and ...
[ Crowd excitement grows ]
Two more humans are in our hands !
[ Shrieks and yells ]
[ Boiling and bubbling ]
[ Harpsichord playing ]
YOYNEH : Go on , go on . Have your bath now .
MAGDA : Then ... then turn your back to me .
YOYNEH : All those ladies and gentlemen
are awaiting you .
Listen ! listen to the music .
[ Shouts ] Come on , take it off !
MAGDA : Don 't you look .
YOYNEH : I 'm not looking . I 'm not looking .
MAGDA : Will I be seeing his excellency ?
YOYNEH : Yes , you 'll see his excellency .
[ Magda gasping ] It 's for me , this lovely dress ?
[ Yoyneh laughing ] Yeah , for you , this lovely dress .
And so are the shoes .
MAGDA : I wonder what his excellency 's like .
Look here ... What are you doing ?
- Oh , no ! [ Slap ] - YOYNEH : Ooh !
Now , listen , I 'm old enough to be your ...
I 'm still your boss , my girl .
MAGDA : If you do that again ,
I 'm telling his excellency .
YOYNEH : Ah , forget your precious excellency
for a minute .
PROFESSOR : Shagal !
Huh ?
What ?
Who spoke ?
PROFESSOR : I did !
Who is speaking , who ?
PROFESSOR : How dare you ask questions , you lech !
Please ! Forgive me !
I didn 't mean to ask questions .
You understand . Thank you .
PROFESSOR : Have you unhitched the horse ?
Horse ? Oy .
I 'll go . I 'll go at once !
No ! Leave it harnessed , you idiot !
Oh , Shagal , about that girl ...
Yeah ?
PROFESSOR : Don 't you touch her again !
I 'm not touching ! Who 's touching ?
[ Clanging ]
Eh ... You pulling my leg , huh ?
[ Chuckles ]
You wouldn 't do a thing like that to Yoyneh ,
huh ? Hey . [ Laughs ]
Answer me . Huh ? [ Chuckles ]
Oy .
PROFESSOR : If they had listened to me ,
all this would never have happened .
ALFRED : Can 't we do anything for her ?
PROFESSOR : Ah ! She 's one of them already .
[ Alfred whispering ] And ... Sarah ?
Quick , professor , quick !
Ah ... The case .
That damned case .
Why did you have to lose it ? !
[ Wolves howl ]
It is I.
Life has a meaning once more .
We are going to save you .
You spoke to her ?
I had a word with her .
After a good transfusion ...
And a few days rest ,
you will be right as rain , my child ... Ooh .
We 've got a congress
in Venice .
The palaces , the sky ,
Venice , Sarah , Venice .
The gondolas ...
The sun !
The sea !
At the next turn , we make for the door .
Light ... Life ... Love .
When I say hop , we make for the door
- and run for it . - Our love .
[ Music dies off ]
Snatch the girl from them !
[ Chuckles ]
[ Crowd gasping ] Aah !
[ Moaning ]
Sharpen your teeth !
The bats !
I 've never come across
such remarkable specimens .
Professor , we haven 't got the time !
I would have to examine them
in detail , of course ,
but here and now I can assert
that we are dealing with Pteropus Poliocephalus ...
We haven 't got the time !
Ooh !
Go .
Mmm ... 1 , 2 , 3 , 4 . Mmm . Good .
[ Crowd approaches ]
[ Thudding ]
[ Kicking ]
[ Crowd approaches ]
Koukol ! Go , Koukol , go !
Give them a little hell , fire , and blood !
Go !
[ Screams ] Catch them !
[ Crashing through trees ]
[ Dogs barking ]
[ Lighthearted music ]
Go ahead , sleep .
Your ... tiny hand ...
It 's frozen !
Professor , she 's ...
her tiny hand is ...
[ Sighs ]
I thought that ...
[ blows ]
My little hand , my pretty hand ...
Soon I will be sleeping ...
[ choking ]
NARRATOR : That night , fleeing from Transylvania ,
Professor Abronsius never guessed
he was carrying away with him
the very evil he had wished to destroy .
Thanks to him ,
this evil would at last be able to spread
across the world .
Captioning made possible by Warner Bros.